Guide to the John Allen Sharpe Papers, 1877-1981 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
John Allen Sharpe papers 1877-1981 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Sharpe, John Allen, 1913-2009.
2.25 Linear Feet approx. 540 Items
John Allen Sharpe was a Duke alumnus who served as editor of the ROBESONIAN newspaper from 1947-1982.
Collection includes correspondence, clippings, and photographs, along with business records for S. A. Edmund & Co.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John Allen Sharpe Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift before 2011 and in 2013.
Biographical Note
John Allen Sharpe was born Oct. 20, 1912. He attended Duke University, graduating at age 19. He served in the Air Corps during World War II. His father, John Allen Sharpe, Sr., was the editor of the ROBESONIAN newspaper from 1907-1947. Upon his father's death, John Allen Sharpe assumed the role of editor. He served in this position from 1947-1982. He was married to Helen Seawell Sharpe and the couple had two sons.
Collection Overview
Collection contains papers related to Sharpe's work as editor. Also includes personal correspondence during the periods Sharpe was a Duke student (1928-1932) and a member of the U.S. Army Air Force (1940s), as well as letters from his wife written while she was on a tour of Europe in 1951, and letters from Sharpe to his parents. There are several copies of the ROBESONIAN, along with postcards, family photographs, and a few published works. In addition, there is a ledger and other records, dated 1887-1892, for S. A. Edmund & Co, a business located in the Lumberton area. A letter and 23 other pages, all undated, containing political speeches hand copied and laid-in to the ledger.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Sharpe, John Allen, 1913- 2009
Duke University -- Students
Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae
Robesonian.
Europe -- Description and travel
Robeson County (N.C.) -- History
Photographs
Postcards
Ledgers
Speeches
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Schoolwork, 1925 and undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, personal, undated
  - Correspondence, personal, 1918-1927
  - Correspondence, personal, 1928-1932
  - Correspondence, personal, 1941-1945
  - Correspondence, personal, 1945-1946
  - Correspondence, personal, 1948-1951
  - Correspondence between family members, 1945-1947 and undated
  - Photographs, undated
  - Biographical Sketches, 1964 and undated
  - Correspondence, professional, 1967-1969
  - Correspondence, professional, 1970-1971
  - Southern Newspaper Publishers Association, 1949
  - Southern Newspaper Publishers Association, 1969 (2 folders)
  - Brochures, Programs, and Informational Materials, 1951-1968
  - Brochures, Programs, and Informational Materials, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Brochures, Programs, and Informational Materials, 1970-1973
  - Brochures, Programs, and Informational Materials, undated
  - Note to self regarding editors selected, 1981
  - Draft of newspaper articles, undated
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1928-1969 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1979-1981
  - ROBESONIAN, Historical and Pictorial Edition, 1932
  - ROBESONIAN, 1951 Feb. 26
  - S. A. Edmund & Co. ledger and records, speeches and letter, 1877-1891 and undated